(忆往昔)
我想这俩就是约翰·温彻斯特的孩子们
Yeah, I think these are John Winchester's boys.
我叫埃伦  这是我女儿  乔
Hey, I'm Ellen. That's my daughter, Jo.
真该狠狠揍你一顿
What can of whup ass I ought to open on you.
-你最好给我电话设个快捷键  -遵命
- You better put me on speed dial, kid. - Yes, ma'am.
外面那些可是地狱犬  迪恩
Those are hellhounds out there, Dean.
我们放狗进来  你们趁机溜到
We let the dogs in, you guys make a break
旁边那栋楼里
for the building next over,
我可以在这里准备引爆
and I can wait here with my finger on the button.
若我能为大家争取到杀掉路西法的机会
If I can get us a shot on the devil,
那就要好好把握
we have to take it.
我不会让你一个人留在这里
But I will not leave you here alone.
-上面正在进行内战  -我知道
- It's civil war up there! - I know.
如果能打败拉斐尔  就能结束这一切
If we can beat Raphael, we can end this!
你不仅仅是叛变
You did more than rebel.
你撕毁了整个剧本
You tore up the whole script
改变了我们所有人的命运
and burned the pages for all of us.
你知道灵魂价值几何吗
Do you have any idea what souls are worth?
知道它们有多大力量吗
What power they hold?
见过这个人吗
Have you seen this man?
-鲁弗斯·特纳  -没有
- Rufus turner? - No.
我没要你帮我
I ain't asking for no help.
从没见过这混混
Never seen that dick.
我又没求你批准
I'm not asking for your permission.
就像以前一样
Just like old times.
车要我来开
Long as I get to drive.
-你是什么  -夏娃把我造出来的
- What are you? - Eve cooked me up herself.
我们的母亲
The mother of all of us,
她让我捎句话给你们
she has a message for you.
都是我的错
It was my fault.
(如今)
(宾夕法尼亚州  切斯特)
真是破烂
Piece of crap.
我日
Damn it.
[邪恶力量 第6季第17集]
说话啊
Say something.
你来
You.
不  你说
No. You.
你俩是打算像毕业舞会上的
You two just gonna stand there
两个丑妹子一样傻站着  还是过来帮忙
like the ugly girl at the prom, or you gonna pitch in?
这什么夏娃  什么之母
This so-called Eve, mother, whatever
可不会自己乖乖消失
ain't gonna gank herself.
你俩怎么了
What's wrong with you two?
鲍比  你好几天没睡了
Bobby, you haven't slept in days.
我有睡  你干嘛  扮我老婆吗
I sleep. What are you, my wife now?
我只是想说
I'm just saying that, you know,
休息一下会比较好
taking five might be a good thing.
对谁好
For whom?
听着  鲍比
Look, Bobby,
那事对我们来说都不好过
it was -- it was tough for all of us,
鲁弗斯就这么走了
seeing Rufus go like that.
你认为...
You think this --
这跟鲁弗斯没关系
This ain't about Rufus.
鲍比  他不仅仅只是个牌友
Bobby, he wasn't just a poker buddy.
我早就知道鲁弗斯会完蛋
You know when I knew Rufus was done for?
遇见他那天起我就知道
The day I met him.
唯一的问题是  他和我谁先玩儿完
The only question was, who first -- him or me?
你们是准备站在那里继续跟我谈心
Now, you want to stand there and therapize,
还是去给我弄点咖啡
or you want to get me some coffee?
要爱尔兰式的
Make it Irish.
他可真好的不得了
Well, he's doing fantastic.
是啊  跟鲁弗斯完全无关
Yeah. This isn't about Rufus at all.
你想怎么做
Well, what do you want to do?
我们可不能眼睁睁看着
I mean, we can't just sit here
他把肝喝爆吧
and watch him poop out his liver.
我们可以让他出去走走
Well, we could get him out of the house.
有个活儿
There's a job.
真的  是什么
Really? what do you got?
看
Look.
宾夕法尼亚州的切斯特
Chester, Pennsylvania.
上周死了三个人
Three people got kicked off in the last week,
死法都很诡异
all freaky.
上一个死的人被自己车库门斩首了
Last guy got karate-chopped by his garage door.
而且这些人都是血亲
And these are all blood relatives.
-你怎么想  家族诅咒吗  -可能
- What are you thinking, family curse? - Could be.
喂  火爆男...
Hey, grumpy --
你
You, uh --
我啥都不想干  别烦我
I don't want to do crap. Leave me alone.
离开我家就是了  你俩
Just...get out of my house, both of you.
可闹心死我了
You're driving me nuts.
鲍比
Bobby.
快点
Now!
我嘞个去
For the love of pete.
也许我们应该等到她回来
You know, maybe we should wait till she gets back.
老兄  她刚在路上打了电话
Dude, she just called from the road,
说她还两步就到了
said she'd be here in "Two shakes."
你真想呆在这里
You really want to sit around
闻他的酒气  看他自怨自艾么
and smell him stew in his juices?
好吧  开车吧
Yeah, yeah. Drive.
怎么...
What the...
别告诉我你一直在喝酒
Tell me you haven't been drinking this whole time.
你比那俩兄弟还烦  我工作呢
You're worse than the boys. I'm working.
我的天
My god.
我就离开一星期  这地方就这德行了
I'm gone a week, and this place goes completely to hell.
你犯什么病  鲍比·辛格
What is wrong with you, Bobby Singer?
拿好笔  要记的可多了
Get a pen. It's a long list.
你闻起来就像个酒吧  知道吗
You smell like a bar, you know that?
你闻起来也没那么香
You don't exactly smell like a rose yourself.
是啊  我一直在和乔猎魔
Huh. Yeah, I been hunting with Jo.
你又因为什么
What's your excuse?
非要说的话  我倒有个不错的理由
If I need one, I got a good one.
我知道
I know.
我很遗憾
and I'm so sorry.
他对我也很重要
He meant a lot to me, too.
梳洗一下  我弄点吃的
Go wash up. I'll fix us something.
有人说过你很烦吗
Anybody ever tell you you're a pain in the ass?
所以你才会娶我啊
That's why you married me.
去吧
Go.
别对我指手画脚的  埃伦
Don't tell me what to do, Ellen.
(宾夕法尼亚州  切斯特)
完全没反应
Not a bleep.
那就说不是复仇鬼魂了
Well, not a vengeful spirit, then.
那是什么
So what is it?
找到啥了
Whatcha got?
这是什么  圣诞节装饰
What is that, christmas tinsel?
我不知道
I don't know.
是金的
It's gold.
你是说  黄金那种
You mean, like, gold gold?
为什么一个杂工的车库里会随地扔金子
Why would a handyman have gold just lying around in his garage?
谁知道呢
I don't know.
他们家族绝对有不可告人的秘密
There is definitely a skeleton in this family's closet.
世上哪儿有那么巧合的意外
I mean, accidents don't just happen accidentally.
你知道我想说什么
You know what I mean.
行了  不如我去查家族档案
All right. How about I'll go check family records,
你走访下近亲
you go with next of kin?
好
Yeah.
这是司法程序  为了证词呀
On the courthouse steps -- for the deposition.
不  我说过了  下午3点
No, I told you, 3:00 P.M.
不  按常价收费
No, my usual fees.
我得挂了  妈
I got to go, ma.
不好意思  您是哪个部门
I'm sorry. Uh, what department?
系谱学  大学里的
Genealogy. From the university.
我们在做一项关于本地家族的研究
W-w-we're doing a study on local families,
鲁索可是大家族
and, well, the Russos are a big one...
这么说吧  我只能说
Yeah, you know what? I got to tell you,
我现在特别忙
I am extremely busy right now, so...
我了解  你这周很不好过
Yeah, I-I'm sure you've had a rough week.
我看到了前阵那些惨剧的报道
I, uh, read about the recent tragedies.
是你的堂亲吧
Your cousins, right?
是的  很遗憾
Yeah. It's a shame.
但我跟他们走得不是很近  所以呢
But I'm not that close with my family, so, uh...
需要很长时间吗
Is this gonna take long?
不会  5分钟  5分钟就好
No. Five minutes. Five minutes.
你能不能跟我说说
Uh, can you -- can you tell me
鲁索家有什么值得关注的事
anything noteworthy about the Russos?
值得关注吗  没有
Noteworthy? No.
也不是不值一提  就很普通啦
I mean, not exactly -- average,
大家族  意大利裔
you know, big, from Italy.
明白
I see.
有人在战争或者其他暴力事件中
Uh, was anyone ever killed or maimed in a war
死去或致残吗
or... you know, some other violent thing?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
就是黑历史  会玷污后代名声的事
Like something so dark that it would sully future generations.
没有
No.
很好  好事
Good. Good stuff.
有人拥有过黑奴吗
Anyone own a slave?
什么
What?
常规问题
Routine question.
跟纳粹党有过瓜葛吗
Any ties to the Nazi party?
你说什么
Excuse me?
祖母开罪过吉普赛人吗
Did grandma ever piss off a Gypsy?
好了  打住
Okay, you know what?
我不管你这做的是什么研究
I don't know what kind of study you're doing,
都给我到此为止  劳您大驾...
but it's over right now, so, if you don't mind...
我还是直说了吧
Okay, I-I'll just cut to the chase here.
你有生命危险
Um, your life is in danger.
什么  这算什么  威胁吗
What? What is that, a-a threat?
你在威胁我吗
Are you threatening me?!
没  没没没有  我不是在威胁你
No, no, no. No, no. I'm not threatening you.
我只是告诉你
I'm just simply saying that...
如果你不留神  就会死掉
If you don't watch your back, you're gonna die.
从我办公室里滚出去
Get the hell out of my office.
-好吧  -马上滚
- Okay. - Now!
-喂  -萨姆
- Hey. - Sam.
有线索吗
Find anything?
找到衣冠二货一只  你呢
One ass-hat in a shiny suit. You?
不多  曾祖父母生于卡拉布里亚
Not much. Great grandparents born in Calabria.
1912年移民到此定居
Emigrated 1912. Been here ever since.
居然跟黑手党没关系
What, no severed horse head?
四代人都种花
Ha. Four generations of picket fence.
要是他家历史这么清白
If these people are the Waltons,
怎么会批量横死
then why the hell are they dying?
那古巴怎么样
Well, how about Cuba?
现在那边风景正好
It's beautiful this time of year.
还有新建的赌场度假城哦  特赞
And the new trump casino -- amazing.
不用担心孩子  那有冲浪池
Don't worry about the kids. There's a wave pool.
没问题  好的
Oh! Sure, yeah!
如果你喜欢雪茄  雪利酒或者马戏表演
Look, if you like cigars, cher, or the circus,
哈瓦那就是最佳选择
It's all about Havana.
对  夏特纳的广告我看见了
Yes, I've seen the Shatner ads.
可是你知道他们欠缺什么吗
But you know what they don't have?
深心接触
Personal touch.
好的  我会把具体细节邮件给你
Okay, then. I'll e-mail you some details.
你也是哦
You too.
安妮·韦萍
Anne Witting.
确定她不是鲁索家亲戚吗
We sure she's not a Russo,
或许是七舅老爷的外甥女呢
a second cousin twice removed or something?
不  我查过两次  她跟他们没有血缘关系
No, I checked the records twice. She's not related.
不是家族诅咒  那又是什么
Oh, if this isn't a family curse, then what the hell is it?
问住我了
You got me.
完全没头绪
I got nothing.
等等
Hold on.
找到一条线索
Not nothing.
然后我们又发现一根
So, we found another piece of this,
这种小亮线
I don't know, shiny string.
我正担心这事
I was afraid of that.
为什么  怎么了
Why? What's up?
全国都出现了这种所谓的意外
Oh, these so-called accidents -- we're seeing 'em nationwide.
目前大概有75桩了
About 75 so far.
乔她们正在加利福尼亚调查其中一批
I got Jo and her crew working on a cluster in California.
是血亲吗
Blood relatives?
有些是  有些不是
Some yeah, some no.
她的发现跟你们类似
She's got about what you do...
死人一堆  金线一把
pile of bodies and a whole bunch of gold thread.
-到底什么意思  -不清楚
- So what's it mean? - I don't know.
鲍比正在查
I got Bobby working on it right now.
顺便问一声  他怎么样
How's he doing, by the way?
别担心
Oh, don't worry.
我正把他踹向健康快乐的轨道上去呢
I'm kicking his ass back to health and happiness.
谁求你来着  狗拿耗子
Who asked you to? To hell with you.
我听到了
I heard that.
他会好起来的
He'll be okay.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
宝贝  真贴心
Oh, honey, you're sweet.
你了解我的  我担心的是你们两个
You know me. I just worry about you boys.
那么  这些死者
All right, so, all these corpses...
有什么共同点吗
anything relate 'em?
事实上  我查到一条
Well, actually, I did dig up one thing.
只是不清楚该作何解释
I just don't know what to make of it.
说吧
Hit me.
很诡异的一件事  不容易发现
Well, it's a weird one, and it was buried pretty deep,
但是我和鲍比查死者族谱的时候
but Bobby and me were combing through
逐渐发现
the family trees on all the victims, and we started seeing,
那些家庭都在同一年到的美国
Well, the families all came over to America the same year.
对  1912年
Yeah. 1912.
但更奇怪的地方是
But here's the real weird part --
他们坐的是同一艘船
they all came over on the same boat.
-真的  -对
- Really? - Yep.
好吧  那这艘船有什么特别
All right, so what's so special about the boat?
没什么特别  就是一艘船
Nothing. It was a boat.
和普通的船没两样
It did what boats do.
这艘船叫什么
What was it called?
泰坦尼克  你听说过吗
The Titanic. You ever hear of it?
没有
No.
我也没有
Yeah, me neither.
我会继续查的
I'll keep digging.
好的
All right.
你知道泰坦尼克吗
Does the name Titanic ring a bell?
泰坦尼克
Titanic?
不知道
No.
皇家邮轮泰坦尼克号
"The RMS Titanic
是当时世界上最大的客轮
"was the largest passenger steamship in the world
在1912年进行了首航
"when it made its maiden voyage
横跨了北大西洋
across the north Atlantic in 1912."
有啥大不了的
So what's the big friggin' deal?
一艘船  开航很正常
It's a ship. It sailed.
对  我也不知道
Yeah, I don't know.
好像有过一场虚惊
Oh, looks like there was a close call.
轮船差点撞上冰山
Ship almost hit an iceberg.
差点  然后呢
Almost? So?
然后
So, uh,
好像大副及时发现了冰山
looks like the first mate spotted it just in time.
干得不错嘛  还有什么吗
Good for him. There anything else?
等等
Wait a second.
怎么了
What?
这个大副  I.P.斐利先生
Uh, this first mate -- Mr. I.P. Freeley.
这有啥好怀疑的
Well, that's not suspicious.
能找到斐利以前的照片吗
You got a picture of old Freeley?
坑爹呢吧
Oh, you got to be kidding me.
我看看
Let's see.
巴尔萨泽
Balthazar.
两位小哥  有什么可以效劳的
Boys, boys, boys. Whatever can I do for you?
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
迪恩  你看起来很心烦啊
Oh, you seem upset, Dean.
巴尔萨泽  那艘船是怎么回事
The hell with the boat, Balthazar.
什么船
What boat?
泰坦尼克
The Titanic.
对哈  泰坦尼克
Yeah. The Titanic.
本来是要沉没的  但是被我救了
Yes, well, uh, it was meant to sink, and I saved it.
什么
What?
本来是要撞上冰山
It was meant to bash into this iceberg thing
带着一船人沉入海底
and plunge into the briny deep with all this hoopla,
但是被我救了
and I saved it.
还有什么疑惑需要解答吗
Anything else I can answer for you?
为什么
Why?
什么为什么
Why what?
你为什么要救这艘船
Why did you un-sink the ship?
因为我讨厌那部电影
Oh, because I hated the movie.
-什么电影  -这就对了
- What movie? - Exactly.
等等  你救这艘轮船的原因是
Wait, so you saved a cruise liner because...
因为席琳·迪翁那首坑爹的歌
Because that god-awful Celine Dion song
让我想自挂东南枝
made me want to smite myself.
谁是席琳·迪翁
Who's Celine Dion?
她是魁北克某个酒吧的穷歌手
Oh, she's a destitute lounge singer somewhere in Quebec,
拜托  就让她继续这样吧
and let's keep it that way, please.
好吧  我觉得不太可能
Okay, I didn't think that was possible.
我以为你无法改变历史
I thought you couldn't change history.
你们没注意到吗
Oh, haven't you noticed?
孩子们  规矩已经都废了
There's no more rules, boys.
你胆子可真大
The nerve on you.
你就这样  救了一艘巨轮
So you just, what, un-sunk a giant boat?
拜托  我可是救了人命
Oh, come on. I saved people.
你们不是喜欢救人吗
I thought you loved that kind of thing.
但是现在  那些人的孩子
Yeah, but now those people and their kids
他们的子子孙孙
and their kids' kids --
他们已经和千千万万的人产生了联系
They must have interacted with so many other people,
改变了很多事情
changed so much crap,
你的一个举动完全改变了历史
you totally butterfly-effected history!
老弟  老弟
Dude. Dude.
规则一  不准提到库奇
Rule one, no Kutcher references.
很不幸  艾什顿·库奇(《蝴蝶效应》男主角)还是存在
Ah, yes. Unfortunately, there's still an Ashton Kutcher.
你们依然阻止了天启
And you still averted the apocalypse,
大天使依旧存在
and there are still archangels.
改变的只是一些小细节而已
It's just the small details that are different,
比如你们开的车不是黑斑羚
like you don't drive an Impala.
你们要问"黑斑羚是什么"
Yes, yes. "What's an Impala?"
相信我  这不重要
Trust me, it's not important.
还有  埃伦和乔都活着
And, of course, Ellen and Jo are alive.
埃伦和乔  怎么回事
Ellen and Jo? What?
她们本应该死了
Yes, they're supposed to be dead.
我救了一艘船  一件事引发另一件
You see, I save a boat, one thing leads to another,
就这样产生连锁效应
which leads to another thousand things,
等等诸如此类
and yada, yada, yada.
长话短说
To cut a long story short,
他们不用死于那场大爆炸
they don't die in a massive explosion.
不管怎样  就算我做了一件好事吧
Anyway, let's agree I did a good thing.
少了一部比利·赞恩的电影
One less Billy Zane movie,
我还救了你们最好的两个朋友
and I saved two of your closest friends.
但是现在有人在追杀
But now somebody is killing
这些幸存者的后代
the descendants of the survivors.
然后呢
And?
大概有五万人
And that's maybe like 50,000 people.
然后
And?
我们必须尽最大努力去救人
And we need to save as many as we can,
但是我们得知道谁在追杀他们
but we need to know who's after 'em.
抱歉
Oh, oh, sorry.
你们把我当成另外一个天使了吗
You have me confused with the other angel --
那个穿着脏兮兮的风衣
you know, the one in the dirty trenchcoat
爱你爱得死去活来的天使
who's in love with you.
我
I...
可不在乎
Don't care.
再见  孩子们
Goodbye, boys.
等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
你个混蛋
Son of a bitch!
巴尔萨泽救了一艘船
So, Balthazar un-sank a boat,
现在就冒出来一整船
and now we got a boatload of people
本不该出生的人
who should never have been born.
对  大概有五万人
Yeah. Like 50,000.
这就说得通了
Makes sense.
这哪儿说的通了啊
How does any of this make sense?
因为我知道我们的对手是谁了
Because I got an idea who we're up against.
什么
What?
命运
Fate.
你是说...
You mean...
我是说命运之神
I mean fate, like the fates.
起码是其中之一
Or one of 'em, at least.
是说希腊神话中的命运三女神么
You mean like greek mythology? Like the sisters?
是
Bingo.
书呆子
Nerd.
她们的职责就是
These ladies are responsible
编织你的命运
for how you go down, literally.
所以  如果有人被车库门压扁
So if you get creamed by a garage door
或者被打印机绞死
or crunched by a copy machine,
而这些死法的细节都是由她们设计
they're the ones who hammer out the details of how you die.
把你的命运纺到一块纯金里
Spin out your fate on a piece of pure gold.
金线
Gold thread.
然后其中一个会把这些都记录在
And then one of 'em writes it all down
她的死亡记录本上
in her day runner of death.
很高级的
High-level stuff.
反正  很符合
Anyway -- fits.
现在我们知道巴尔萨泽曾经做了什么
Now we know what Balthazar did.
要我说
It seems to me
可能命运之神在收拾这烂摊子
that maybe fate is just trying to clean up the mess.
那我们怎么制止她呢
So, how do we stop it?
如何阻止命运  问得好
How do we stop fate? Good question.
肯定会有办法
Well, there's got to be a way.
要是没呢
Or there ain't.
我们在讨论的可是命运女神
I mean, this is fate we're talking about here.
最简单的方法就是
You know, the easiest way would be
让那天使把那船弄沉
to get that angel to re-sink the boat.
不可能  想都别想
No. No way. Forget it.
惨死和根本不出生
Big difference
这两者可有很大区别  迪恩
between dying awful and never being born, Dean.
鲍比  我们不能让船沉没
We are not sinking the boat, Bobby.
听到没  想都别想
Okay? Don't even think about it.
好吧  你小子急个什么劲儿
Well, okay. What's got your panties in a clench?
没什么
Nothing.
还想蒙我
Try that again?
这个
It --
听着  这没什么关系  但是
Look, it -- it -- it doesn't even really matter, but...
但是什么
But?
很明显  如果泰坦尼克沉了
Apparently, a crap-load of dominoes get tipped over
那么情况就会全部反过来
if the titanic goes down.
结果就是...
And, bottom line...
埃伦和乔都会死
...Ellen and Jo die.
好的  你们俩个听好了
Okay, you two. Listen up.
你们要确保
You make sure...
绝对不能让那些天使弄沉那艘船
keep those angels from sinking that boat.
明白吗
You understand me?
好的
Yeah. Yes.
当然了  鲍比
Yeah, Bobby, of course.
有她在  他还这德行呢
Oh, he's bad enough with her.
要是她不在  他得成什么样
Think how he'd be if she was gone.
是呀
Yeah.
那我们怎么办
So, what do we do?
我的意思是  我们怎么救五万人
I mean, how do we save 50,000 people?
完全没头绪
I got no freakin' clue.
我们连他们是谁都不知道
Yeah. We don't even know who they are.
有一个我们知道
Well, we know one.
就是他  走
That's him. Let's go.
你好
Hello.
什么
Yeah. What?
鲁索先生
Mr. Russo!
我不管  给他送个水果蛋糕
I don't care. Send him a fruitcake.
-肖恩  -谁是法官
- Shawn! - Who's the judge?
鲁索
Russo!
那好  送他瓶上好的香槟好了
All right, send him a nice bottle of champagne.
但是别超过30块  啊不  20块就行
But nothing more than $30 -- ah, no. 20 bucks.
相信我  这家伙欠我个人情
Believe me, this guy -- he owes me a favor.
鲁索  停下
Russo, stop!
放开我
Get off of me.
还有你  不是告你别来找我吗
And you -- I told you to leave me alone, didn't I?!
听着  我们只是想帮你
Look, we're just trying to help you out, okay?
帮我  你们差点害死我  你个疯子
Help me?! You almost killed me, you lunatic.
拿来  真是难以置信
Give me that. Unbelievable.
鲁索
Russo! Hey!
没起诉你够不错了
Just be glad I'm not suing your ass!
开什么玩笑
You've got to be kidding me.
萨姆  快看
Sam, check it out.
什么
What?
(免费咨询  人身伤害以及异常死亡)
不太合适吗
Too soon?
嗯  迪恩
Yeah, dean.
我肯定才过六秒确实不太合适
I'm pretty sure six seconds is too soon.
喂  喂
Hey. Hey, hey, hey.
我好像看到她了
I think I saw her.
刚刚就在那里
Right over there.
-她  命运女神吗  -是的
- Her? Like fate her?  -Yeah.
她什么样
What'd she look like?
看起来像是图书馆员
Kind of like a librarian.
是你那种  还是我那种
Your kind of librarian or my kind of librarian?
好吧  她穿着衣服呢
Well, she was wearing clothes,
如果你是想问这个
if that's what you mean.
好吧
All right.
等等  我们不能就这么过去吧
Wait, wait, wait. We can't just walk over there.
咱们又不在追杀名单里
We're not on the hit list.
那船跟我们没关系
We have nothing to do with the boat.
过去和她谈谈
Let's go talk to her.
谈谈
Talk.
是啊  你看
Yeah, you know.
谈谈而已  值得一试  对吧
Talk. Worth a shot, right?
有人吗
Hello?
有人在吗
拜托
Oh, come on.
有打火机吗
You got a lighter?
有
Yeah.
我说  没气儿了还是怎么着
Oh, come on. It's out of juice or something?
不应该啊
It shouldn't be.
小卡
Cass!
你们好  迪恩  萨姆
Hello, Dean. Sam.
嘿  干的漂亮
Hey, nice man.
我们在哪
Where are we?
白俄罗斯
White Russia.
什么
What?!
你知道你那兄弟都做了什么吗
Are you aware of what your frat bro did?
我知道  巴尔萨泽是有点冲动
I'm aware. Balthazar can be impetuous.
那你猜猜
Well, riddle me this --
如果命运女神的目标是和船有关的那些人
If fate's going after the boat people,
又为何要杀我和萨姆
why'd she try to waste me and Sam?
我想她对你们俩
Well, I imagine she harbors
心怀一定程度的痛恨
a certain degree of rage toward you.
我们做错什么了
What did we do?
没什么大不了的  不过就是
Nothing of import -- just the tiny matter
阻止天启  导致她再无用处
of averting the apocalypse and rendering her obsolete.
我想她对此有点恼羞成怒吧
I think maybe she's a little irritated about that.
而你们俩还主动送上门
And then you go and dangle yourselves in front of her...
原来命运女神和我们是有私仇啊
So we've pissed fate off personally.
就我对她的了解
If I know her -- and I do --
不见你们俩尸骨她不会善罢甘休
She won't stop until you're dead.
真好
Awesome.
那我们怎么做
So what do we do?
杀了她
Kill her.
杀死命运女神吗
Kill fate?
你还有何高见
Do you have another suggestion?
不  我  意思是
No, I'm -- I just mean, uh...
命运女神杀得死吗
Can you even do that?
巴尔萨泽有能对付她的武器
Balthazar has a weapon that will work against her.
那是当然了
Of course he does. Yeah.
找他就找对人了  是吧
Boy, that guy's just got it covered, doesn't he?
你得交些新朋友  小卡
You need new friends, Cass.
我这是在救我朋友的命  迪恩
I'm trying to save the ones I have, Dean.
我们得诱她出动
We'll have to draw her out.
既然她想伺机加害我们
All right, well, uh, she's gunning for us.
到头来肯定会再露面
She's bound to surface again eventually.
那就帮她一把
We'll make it easy for her.
用你们的话说  就是
I think you have an expression for it.
"诱捕命运女神"
"Tempting fate."
好的  那你自己小心
Yeah, well, you just be careful.
是乔  西海岸又死了30多人
That was Jo. 30 more dead on the West Coast.
这兄弟俩到底知道自己要干什么不
What exactly do those boys think they're gonna do?
他们俩啊
It's the boys.
要说有谁能救他们  也只有他俩了
If anybody can pull this out of their ass, it's those two.
你有听过"命中注定"这说法吗
Yeah, you ever hear the saying "You can't stop fate"?
我说  最利落的解决办法就是让船沉没
You know, cleanest fix would just be to sink the boat.
你怎么能这么说
Why would you say that?
因为现在那些人都一个个惨死
Well, because, right now they're all dying bloody.
这跟他们从未出生可不一样
It's not the same as never being born.
那可都是人命啊
You're talking about people --
有人爱他们
People who are loved...
也有人会想他们
...who would be missed.
你哪根筋不对了
What the hell is up with you?
没事
Nothing.
得了吧  此地无银三百两
Oh, please. You are a neon sign.
是要我动手
So, I can beat it out of you,
还是自己交代  你选吧
or we could just skip that part -- dealer's choice.
所以不只有我  乔也是吗
So, not just me, but Jo, too?
他们不会让船沉没的  我保证
They're not gonna sink the boat. I promise.
船在  你就不用担心
The boat stays. You don't have to worry.
如果命运本该如此  那
If it was meant to be, then...
我猜是祸躲不过
I guess whatever happens, happens.
所以说啊  没什么"命中注定"
But that's just my point. Nothing's "Meant to be."
我们分开与否全在一个混蛋天使一时兴起
Whether we're together is at the whim of some dick angel.
鲍比  别紧张
Oh, Bobby, relax.
我不能
I can't.
我们需要你
We need you.
尤其是我
Especially me.
我知道
I know.
我们随时都会遭遇"命运的邂逅"  是吧
Okay, so, we're just gonna meet our fate at any time, right?
没错
Yeah.
继续走  自然点
Just walk. Act natural.
好吧
Okay.
没事
That's fine.
是坑爹呢吧
Oh, you got to be kidding me.
好的  继续  走着
All right, just -- just keep walking.
萨姆  他们在耍刀呢
Sam, they're juggling knives.
-还有短斧  -我知道
- And hatchets. - Yeah, I know.
是祸躲不过
Can't avoid fate.
好吧  我不明白
All right. I don't get it.
我也没明白
I don't either.
我们都送上门儿了  怎么还不动手
Who do you got to kill to get killed around here?
也许小卡想错了
Maybe Cass was wrong.
当心
Look out!
卡西迪奥
Castiel.
阿特洛波斯
Atropos.
气色不错
You look well.
多亏了你啊  我现在屁都不是
I look like stomped-over crap, because of you.
好吧  我们谈谈
All right, let's talk about this.
谈  谈什么
Talk? About what?
谈你和你的这两只马戏团小丑
Maybe about how you and those two circus clowns
是如何破坏我的工作的吗
destroyed my work.
你们毁掉了我的生活
You ruined my life.
不要激动
Let's not get emotional.
说什么不要激动
Not get emotional?!
我有份工作
I had a job.
承蒙上帝安排
God gave me a job.
我们应各司其职
We all had a script.
我辛勤工作
I worked hard.
还干得不错
I was really, really good at what I did...
直到晴天霹雳从天而降
Until the day of the big prize fight.
发生了什么呢  你破坏了一切秩序
And then what happens? You throw out the book!
听着  我很抱歉
Well, I'm sorry.
但自由价更高
But freedom is more preferable.
自由  这是混乱  哪里好了
Freedom? This is chaos! How is it better?
我甚至上天堂
You know, I even went to heaven
只为得到下一步的行动指示  可是呢
just to ask what to do next, and you know what?
都没人跟我搭话
No one would even talk to me.
大家手边都有更紧迫的事要处理
There are more pressing matters at hand.
可我不知道接下来会发生什么
But I don't know what happens next.
我需要知道  这是我的工作
I need to know. It's what I do.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
但你被解雇了
But your services are no longer required.
知道吗
You know what?
我一直闭口不谈
I've kept my mouth shut.
我可以怨声载道  我可以小题大做
I could have complained, I could have raised a fuss,
但我没有
But I didn't.
可你知道底线是什么吗
But you know what the last straw is?
拯救泰坦尼克号
Un-sinking the Titanic.
你改变了未来  但不能重写历史
You changed the future. You cannot change the past.
太过分了
That is going too far!
-是巴尔萨泽干的  他不受控制  -狗屁
- It's Balthazar. He's erratic -- - Bull crap.
跟那部破电影根本没关系
This isn't about some stupid movie.
他听命于你
He's under your orders.
是你派他拯救了那艘游轮
You sent him back to save that ship.
不是我
No, I didn't.
我为什么要那么做
Why would I?
大概是因为你身陷战争之中
Oh, maybe because you're in the middle of a war
只能孤注一掷
and you're desperate?
得了吧  明明就是为了那些灵魂
Come on. This is about the souls.
简直是一派胡言
You don't know what you're talking about.
那个天使为你们的战争机器
That angel went and create
增添了5万灵魂
50,000 new souls for your war machine.
你搞错了
You're confused.
我没有
No.
你不能这样快速增员  卡西迪奥
You can't just mint money, Castiel.
这是不道德的...
It's wrong...
也是危险的...
It's dangerous...
我不会让你得逞的
and I won't let you.
你没有选择的权利
You don't have a choice.
也许我是没有
Maybe I don't.
但我可以让你选
So here's a choice for you.
如果你不回到过去  让那艘船沉没
If you don't go back and sink that boat,
我会杀了你最中意的两个小宠物
I'm gonna kill your two favorite pets.
我不会让你得逞
I won't let you.
是吗  你能拿我怎样
Oh, yeah? What are you gonna do?
别把我逼急了
Do you really want to test me?
好吧
Okay. Fine.
但你要知道...
But think about this...
我有两位姐姐
I've got two sisters out there.
她们比我大  而且不仅是在年龄方面
They're bigger, in every sense of the word.
杀了我...
Kill me...
萨姆和迪恩会是她们的首要目标
Sam and Dean are target one.
纯粹是为了报仇
For simple vengeance.
你目前没在忙着打仗什么的  对吧
You're not fighting a war or anything, right?
你可以夜以继日  寸步不离地保护他们
You can watch them every millisecond of every day.
因为你可能听说过...
Because maybe you've heard...
命运总会在最不经意时眷顾
Fate strikes when you least expect it.
巴尔萨泽  住手
Balthazar, stop.
尴尬了
Awkward.
快把事情矫正回来
Set things right
不然我就按规矩  把你的两个小心肝做掉
before I flick your precious boys off a cliff just on principle.
亲爱的  在我们走之前...
Uh, sweetie, before we go, um,
我可以帮你把那树枝拿走...
I could remove that stick from your...
别逼我
Don't try me.
那还是留着吧
Oh. We'll leave it inserted, then.
那好
All right, then.
咱去把泰坦尼克号搞沉吧
Let's sink the Titanic.
哥们儿  几点了
Dude, what time is it?
我刚刚做了个超级诡异的梦
I-I just had the weirdest dream.
赌20块  我的更诡异  不开玩笑
20 bucks says mine was weirder. I am not kidding.
不  我也没开玩笑
No, no. I'm not kidding, either.
那个梦...
I-I mean, it was...
真的很怪
just bizarre.
我梦到真正的泰坦尼克号了
Mine had the actual Titanic in it.
怎么了
What?
我脸上有脏东西吗
Something on my face?
它是不是...
D-did it, uh...
...没沉
...not sink,
因为巴尔萨泽
because Balthazar...
不喜欢比利·赞恩(《泰坦尼克》中露丝的未婚夫)吗
had a hate on for Billy Zane?
咱俩的梦怎么一模一样  哥们
Why are you having my dreams, dude?
那不是个梦
Wasn't a dream.
等等  你说什么
Wait, what?
你是说这些事真的发生过吗
You're saying this actually happened?
这整件...事情都是真的吗
That t-the whole... whatever -- t-that was real?
是的
Yes.
等等  那到底发生了什么
Wait. So, what happened?
我坚持要他及时回到过去
Well, I insisted he go back in time
修正他的所作所为
and correct what he'd done.
什么
What?
为什么
Why?
只有这样才能确保你们的安全
It was the only way to be sure you were safe.
这...
So...
这么说你为了我们...  杀了5万人
So, you killed... 50,000 people for us.
我没有  因为他们从未出生过
No, I didn't. They were never born.
这和被杀截然不同  难道不是么
That's far different from being killed, wouldn't you say?
埃伦和乔呢
Ellen and Jo?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
等等
Hold on.
如果你们回去修正了历史
So, if you guys went a-and changed everything back,
那以前的时间轴就被抹去了吗
then that whole timeline or whatever, it just got erased?
对  差不多吧
Yeah. More or less.
那为什么我们俩还记得
Well, then, how come he and I remember it?
因为我希望你们能记住
Because I wanted you to remember it.
为什么
Why?
我希望你们看清命运的本来面目
I wanted you to know who fate really is.
她既残酷又无常
She's cruel and capricious.
要我说就是"贱人"
I'd go so far as "bitch".
没错
Well, yeah.
是你们教会了我
You're the ones who taught me
命运掌握在自己手中
that you can make your own destiny.
你不必受命运的掌控
You don't have to be ruled by fate.
你可以选择自由
You can choose freedom.
我仍相信那是值得为之拼搏的东西
I still believe that that's something worth fighting for.
我只是想让你们明白这个道理
I just wanted you to understand that.
等等
So, wait.
巴尔萨泽真的
Did...Balthazar really, uh,
就因为一部言情片  弄出这么大动静
unravel the sweater over a chick flick?
是的
Yes.
没错  他就是这样
Absolutely. That's what he did.
你不该让他再看电视了
Wow. Well, might be time to take away his cable privileges.
再说了  《泰坦尼克》也没那么烂
Besides, "Titanic" didn't suck that bad.
温斯莱特胸很大
Winslet's rack.
小卡有一个特点
I'll tell you one thing about Cass,
他不懂得欣赏美好的事物
he does not appreciate the finer things.
一切都恢复正常了吧
I guess things are back to normal, huh?
"正常"  太棒了
"Normal". Awesome.
可怜的家伙
Poor bastard.
甚至都不知道自己曾经那么幸福
Doesn't even know how good he had it.
不知情就不会难过
Yeah, well, what he doesn't know won't hurt him.
咱们最好不要告诉他
I say we keep our mouths shut.
好  听你的
Yeah. I'm with you.
要叫醒他吗
Should we wake him?
别了
Nah.
这大概是他一周以来最舒服的时候了
That's probably the best he's felt all week.